Craig Reese

(630) 621-6577 - reeseca90@gmail.com - https://github.com/reeseca90/ - https://www.linkedin.com/in/craigareese

Professional Summary:

A well-rounded developer with experience building full-stack applications from the ground up using Node.js and React. Prior experience in training, operations, and maintenance of electrical equipment and distribution systems aboard US Naval Vessels and the private sector. Additional skills include:

HTMLMongoDB/NoSQL databasesProblem SolvingCSS/SASSJavaProgram AdministrationJavaScriptRESTful API developmentOutage PlanningReactSecurity ClearanceQuality AssuranceNode.js/ExpressCommunicationsTraining and Instruction

Work Experience:

Maintenance Electrician, Crane Area Lead - JW Aluminum, Aug 2019 - Oct 2020

- Performed preventative and corrective maintenance on all electrical equipment in the rolled aluminum production process to include power distribution, PLCs, AC/DC motors, and AC/DC drives. Coordinated with third-party contractors for the upgrade and installation of new electrical equipment.
- Assigned as lead electrician in the crane department consisting of 18 overhead and 20 pedestal cranes
 running at a continuous duty cycle. Responsible for the planning, parts acquisition, and execution of all
 maintenance and repairs on crane electrical systems.

Class Director and Instructor - Naval Nuclear Power Training Command, U.S. Navy, Nov 2016 - July 2019

- Provided leadership to 70 instructors and advisors in the training and development of 350 newly reporting students, resulting in a 75% reduction in student attrition.
- Managed the assignment and distribution of staff members, enhancing the command's ability to provide instruction to over 3200 students per year.
- Provided classroom instruction to new students in basic electricity and electrical fundamentals, achieving a 100% course pass rate.

Reactor Electrical Leading Petty Officer - USS John C. Stennis, U.S. Navy, Feb 2013 - Nov 2016

- Led 35 employees in the execution of training, qualifications, administration, and maintenance on the electrical systems associated with two nuclear power plants.
- Supervised a 26-person watch team in the routine and emergency operations as a Propulsion Plant Watch Supervisor.
- Interfaced with off-ship organizations in the planning, preparation, execution, and reporting of maintenance events during in-port and shipyard maintenance availabilities.

Electrical Technician and Operator - Nuclear Power Training Unit, U.S. Navy, Sept 2010 - Feb 2013

- Performed preventative and corrective maintenance on electrical and reactor safety equipment.
- Trained students on systems, watch standing, and integrated operations of naval nuclear propulsion plants.

Education:

Trident Technical College, A.A.S. Computer Technology – Computer Programming, 2020-present U.S. Naval Nuclear Power Program, 2008-2010

Montachusett Regional Vocational Technical High School, Information Technology, 2004-2008